"妙警贼探" 前情提要...
Previously on White Collar...
Mosconi法典
The Mosconi Codex.
这可不是一般的书
This is no ordinary book.
- Neal  - 你好 Rebecca
- Neal.  - Hello, Rebecca.
你们俩认识?
You two know each other?
我发誓 我下班的时候还戴着员工卡
I swear, I had my key card when I left work.
我们一旦找出那本书里有什么秘密
We figure out what's hidden in those pages
就能先下手为强
and get to it first.
因为我 那个贼才进来的
I'm the reason the thief got in.
我本来是希望收藏家能让我们看一看
My hope was that the owner would let us study
研究研究那本手抄本的 可现在也不在了
and look at the codex, and now it's gone.
David Siegel 死因是
David Siegel. Cause of death
胸部中枪
was a gunshot wound to the sternum.
凶手是谁 动机何在 我们还是毫无头绪
And we're no closer to figuring out who did this and why.
Summers医生 我需要你的帮助
Dr. Summers, I need your help.
一个人开始做好事
Just because a person starts doing good things
并不意味着就不做坏事了
doesn't mean he wants to stop doing bad things.
我有太多主子了
I've been serving too many masters.
我受够了当每个人的玩偶
I'm through being everyone's puppet.
你到底计划脱离哪一方呢?
Which strings, exactly, do you plan on cutting?
统统再见
All of them.
很不错
连封面上的芯片也跟真的一样
Even the chip in the cover works.
你是怎么做到的?
How'd you pull that off?
我不负责做 只负责卖
I don't make them. I just sell them.
你个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
不许动! 举起手来
Freeze! Hands in the air.
联邦调查局! 不准动!
FBI! Don't move!
他是你的了
He's all yours.
- 干嘛?  - 别装模作样的
- What?  - Don't "what" me.
你知道是干嘛 我告诉你明确步骤了
You know what. I gave you specific instructions.
"坐下 交易 逮捕"
"sit down, make the deal, get arrested."
这三步你哪一步不满意了?
Three out of three not good enough for you?
我可不记得我提过
I don't remember mentioning anything
逮捕前还有什么后续提问
about follow-up questions or interrogating the suspect
- 或是盘问嫌犯  - 盘问嫌...
- before the arrest.  - Interrogating the sus...
你在说什... 哦 芯片?
What are you... What, the chip?
- 就是芯片  - 我在收集信息
- The chip.  - I was gathering information.
- 为局里还是为你自己啊?  - 我要是在打什么主意
- For you or for us?  - If I were up to something,
你真以为我会当着你的面问?
you really think I'd do it when you had ears on me?
你就是会这么干
That's exactly when you'd do it.
我感觉这案子不仅仅是关于伪造护照
I have a feeling this is about more than passports.
就是关于护照 以及上一件案子里
Oh, it's about passports. Also about the $2 million
失踪的200万美金
that went missing in the last case.
Summers医生说不定能靠直觉
Oh, Dr. Summers might have some insight
- 找出它们来  - Summers医生乐于将
- into its location.  - Dr. Summers had a tendency
一心想改头换面的坏人
to take bad guys who wanna be good
变得更坏
and turn them into worse guys.
你的治疗过程中到底发生了什么?
What exactly happened during your therapy session?
她鼓励我做真正的自己
She encouraged me to be the man I really am.
Lucy会对Charlie Brown说这种话
I think Lucy told Charlie Brown that
然后只收5美分?(他们都是史努比里的角色 关系不好)
and only charged him 5 cents?
那准确说来 你真正的自我是什么样呢?
And what kind of man might that be, exactly?
这个问题我们下一疗程再讨论
We were gonna discuss that at our next session.
现在我得再等20年
Now I have to wait 20 years.
我想这大概是Jones的
I think these belong to Jones.
嘿 这些都是哪儿来的?
Hey, where'd you get all these?
全市各地抄查没收来的
Confiscated in various busts around the city.
大多都是过去几星期
Most in the last few weeks.
它们质量一流 且工艺完全相同
It's first-rate and identical.
这些都是同一个人做的
These were all made by the same person.
- 你确定?  - 没错 你看封面上的鹰眼
- You're sure about that?  - Yeah, the eagle's eye.
这一本和我从Ivan手上买到的那本一样
There's a tiny dot in the center of this one
中间都有个小点
and in the one I bought from Ivan.
这个点几乎和指纹一样完美
That dot is as good as a fingerprint.
所以我们面对的是一个相当大的伪造集团
So we're looking at a fairly large forgery operation.
你觉得Ivan是伪造师吗?
You think Ivan's the artist?
不是 他说他只负责卖 我相信他
No, he says he only sells them, and I believe him.
任何一个如此优秀的人都会想居功
Anyone this good would take credit.
你觉得这个与
Think this has something to do
小奥德萨区犯罪率的上升有关吗?
with the uptick of crime in Little Odessa?
我不相信巧合
I don't believe in coincidences.
Ivan的违规停车罚单
Ivan's parking tickets.
今年已经十张了 而且都在
Ten so far this year, and they're all
同一个位置
in the exact same spot.
我需要这条街上
I want traffic surveillance video
过去六个月的监控录像
for the past six months on that address.
这就去办
Already on it.
- 当真?  - 当真
- Really?  - Really.
同一个地点 每天都这样
Same spot, day after day.
就在消防栓跟前
Right in front of the hydrant.
这条街上有很多咪表停车位
There's plenty of metered parking down the street.
为什么甘冒被贴罚单的危险?
Why risk another ticket?
多莉丝·戴停车位
Doris Day parking.
抱歉 多莉丝·戴的啥?
I'm sorry. Doris Day what?
正前方的停车位
Spot right in front.
就是多莉丝·戴在她的每部电影里
The kind of parking doris Day miraculously finds
- 都能神奇地找到的停车位  - 没想到你居然是她粉丝
- in all her movies.  - I never knew you were a fan.
我喜欢那些电影
Oh, I love 'em.
这地方看起来废弃了
Place looks abandoned.
是啊 对于护照伪造集团来说不算糟
Yeah, not a bad spot for a passport forgery operation.
我们去弄张搜查令来检查检查
Let's get a warrant and check it out.
密码使用的历史... 令人惊异地隐秘
The history of cryptography... Oddly cryptic.
进展如何 找出这是哪种密码了吗?
Any luck finding out what type of code this is?
我已经排除了移位式密码和凯撒方阵
Oh, I've ruled out transposition and Caesar shifts.
哦 还有数独以及聪明方格
Oh, and sudoku and kenken.
说不定你无意中还证明了
Well, in a happy accident, you may have proven
黎曼假设呢
the Riemann hypothesis.
我唯一能证明的是我们需要帮助
The only thing I've proven is that we need help.
我研究了每一个图案 每一个符号
I've studied every pattern, every symbol.
只能总结得出 这东西来自外星人
I can only conclude that it is of alien origin.
我觉得你是对的
I think you're right.
啊哈! 你总算醒悟了
Aha! Finally, you've come around.
我觉得你是对的 我们需要帮助
I think you're right. We need help.
哦
Oh.
我倒是认识一个柏林的修道士
Well, I do know a monk in Berlin
对量子力学有所涉猎
who dabbles in quantum mechanics.
你觉得Hagen在利用修道士?
You think Hagen's using monks?
我觉得Hagen在利用你
I think Hagen is using you.
还有我
and me.
率先破解出法典是我们
The only chance we have of getting a leg up on him
扳倒他的唯一机会
is by deciphering the Codex first.
那时...
Until then...
还有很多事情要做
It's ticking clocks and phone calls.
好吧 我得走了
All right, I gotta go.
Peter和我要去找小奥德萨
Peter and I are headed to Little Odessa.
我来跟她说
I do the talking.
我们是来常规检查的
We're just here on a routine visit.
仅此而已
Nothing more.
哦...
Well...
看来不像被废弃了
Doesn't look abandoned.
看来有人重新启用了这里
Looks like someone brought it back to life.
哇 每次我看到冰场
Wow. Every time I see ice like this,
就仿佛回到了童年
I'm ten again.
- 哦 滑得真不错  - 嗯
- Oh, she's good.  - Yeah.
先是多丽丝·戴(德国女导演) 接着又是花样滑冰
First Doris Day, now figure skating.
能看到你柔情面 真是有幸
It's nice to see your softer side.
你们是谁? 找我什么事?
Who are you? What do you want?
我们只想问几个问题
We just have a few questions
关于这座楼的主人
for the owner of this building.
赶紧收起来 要不然我们都有危险
Put that away, or you'll get all of us killed.
嘿!
Hey!
这里是私人领地
This is private facility.
你们不能擅自闯进来
You're trespassing.
我想他们只是走错了
闭嘴 Katya!
我们只想问点事情
We just have a few questions.
想问一下Katya
Questions for Katya,
关于小奥德萨比赛的事情
The talk of Little Odessa.
我是体育经纪人 Neal Micali
Neal Micali, sports agent.
我旗下有很多世界级运动员
I represent some of the world's top athletes.
这位是Peter Nevins
This is Peter Nevins,
明星级花样滑冰教练
figure skating coach to the stars.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 花孔雀 初见 落寞卷菜 猫鼠小贝 爱鼠影 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影
妙警贼探 第五季第6集
Peter Nevins教练?
Peter Nevins, coach?
没听说过
Never heard of you.
是吗? 那你听过塔拉·利平斯基吗?(花滑奥运冠军)
Really? You ever heard of Tara Lipinski?
还有关颖珊?(著名华裔花滑运动员)
Or Michelle Kwan?
如果没有他
They would be ushers at the ice capades
她们只能当场馆引座员
if it weren't for this man.
哦 没错 但...
Oh, yes. He's just...
但... 我只是让她们的天赋
He's just... I simply help them harness
发挥出来
their own natural talents.
不好意思 让你们白来了一趟
Sorry to be wasting your time,
Katya不想参加什么比赛
but Katya has no interest in competing.
求你了 Sergei 我想换教练 我想参加比赛
谢谢你们的好意
Thank you for your interest.
- 但抱歉 请吧...  - 没关系
- Now, if you'll excuse us...  - It's not a problem.
这周还要访问另外20个备选人...
We got another 20 girls to see by the end of the week, so...
- 是27个  - 现在是27个了?
- 27.  - Is it 27 now?
- 是27个  - 听我说...
- It's 27.  - Listen...
你有天赋
you're talented.
非常有天赋
Very talented.
别放弃你的梦想
Don't give up on your dream.
不好意思 耽误彼此的时间了
Sorry we wasted your time and ours.
等等 现在不太方便
Wait. This is not the right time.
但是你们先别选别人
But don't choose another girl yet.
给你
Here.
那我们再联系
We'll be in touch.
- 花样滑冰教练?  - 怎么了?
- Figure skating coach?  - What?
你从当上联邦调查员就开始滑冰了
You've been skating since you were a junior G-man.
但我是打冰球的
But that was hockey.
我们练习的是身体阻挡 不是转圈
We're talking body checks, not twirls.
别这样 这样伪装很好
Oh, come on. It's a good cover.
我才不用伪装 我可以带着特种部队冲进去
I don't need a cover. I could go in there
把里面里里外外搜个遍
with a tac team and turn that place upside down.
如果你想打草惊蛇
Yeah, you could if you wanted to scare off the guys
确实可以这么做
we're really after.
你就承认吧... 这个案子的最佳切入点
Just admit it... best way into this case
是滑冰
is on skates.
你已经入围了
You got a ticket.
你要照张简历照 不是搞怪照片
Come on, this is for your bio, not a mug shot.
- 快点  - 哦 折磨死我了
- Come on.  - Oh, you're killing me.
我没这闲工夫 我还有工作要做
I don't have time for this. I've got asac work.
- 我没工夫玩这些  - 笑一个
- I can't play dress-up.  - Just smile.
Rebecca吗?
Rebecca?
Gershon博物馆的
From the Gershon Museum.
联邦调查局的Neal
Neal, from the FBI.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- Hey.  - Hi.
- 你好吗?  - 我...
- How are you?  - I'm, uh...
一团糟
terrible.
博物馆界的都互相认识
The museum world, it's really small.
很难找到别的工作
I can't get another job.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry to hear that.
我能帮你什么吗?
Is there anything I can do to help?
你? 不用
You?  No.
你做得够多了
You've done enough.
哇...
Whoa. Wha...
我回想了一下
I've been thinking about that day
找不到门卡的那天
that I lost my key card,
我记得最后看到它 就是和你在一起的时候
and you're the last person that I remember having it with.
你不会是觉得我偷了它吧?
What, you don't think I stole it, do you?
我为什么要偷你的门卡? 我可以自由出入博物馆的
Why would I steal your key card? I had full access to the museum.
那天你无缘无故约了我
Nothing about that day makes sense.
我来是为了问点事情...
I'm just here to get some answers and...
我希望Burke探员能给我开个证明信
I was hoping to get a letter from Agent Burke
证明我是清白的
stating my complete innocence.
- 他在那里  - 嗯...
- There he is.  - Uh, yeah, that's...
别这样做
that's a really bad idea.
他正在纠结另一个案子
He is swamped on a new case right now
最好别惹他
and just not in a giving mood.
况且他也不再负责Gershon博物馆案子的调查了
Anyway, he wasn't even in charge of the Gershon investigation.
- 那谁负责?  - Gruetzner探员
- Then who was?  - That would be Agent Gruetzner.
他是艺术品犯罪小组的 不在这里办公
Art crimes. He's not at these offices.
那我要去哪里找...
So where do I find this Agent...
- Gruetzner探员?  - Gruetzner探员
- Gruetzner?  - Gruetzner.
他今天出去办案了
Uh, he is in the field today.
但我可以帮你跟他预约一下明天见面
But I could set something up for tomorrow.
- 好吧  - 好了?
- All right.  - All right?
- 那就明天  - 好的
- Tomorrow.  - Okay.
我把电话号码留给你
Let me give you my number.
然后你把地址发短信给我
You can text me the address.
我们是联邦调查局 当然有你电话
We're the FBI. We have your number.
- 哦  - 你会拿到证明信的
- Ha.  - I'll get you that letter.
什么情况?
What's the story?
这位Sergei Turgenev
Sergei Turgenev.
就是冰场那个能说会道的家伙
Our smooth-talking friend from the ice rink.
从信息局一个朋友那得到的材料
Got that from a friend at FAPSI.
- 那可是俄罗斯情报局  - 俄罗斯情报局
- That's Russian Intelligence.  - Russian Intelligence.
嗯 这里边全是警方的犯罪记录
Yeah, this is the crime and punishment of rap sheets.
这个家伙... 更了不得了
And this guy... is worse.
Sergei的堂弟Nikolai
That's Sergei' s cousin Nikolai.
因谋杀罪被俄国政府通缉
Wanted for murder in Russia.
洗钱 贩毒
Money laundering, drug trafficking,
走私武器 贩运人口
arms trafficking, human trafficking.
基本上 只要是偷渡走私的事都干
Basically, any kind of trafficking.
嗯 到现在为止
- Yeah.  - Nobody knew he was
没人知道他在这儿
in the country until now.
我们不可能给罪犯签证
We don't give visas to criminals,
他要么是偷渡过来...
so either he snuck in on a tuna boat...
要么就是用Sergei的护照
Or he flew here first-class
坐着头等舱过来的
using one of Sergei' s passports.
问题是.. .如果Sergei能神不知鬼不觉把Nikolai带进来
Question is... if Sergei can bring Nikolai in here
他还打算把谁弄进来呢?
without us knowing, who else is he planning to import?
如果我事先知道这个
If I had known about this,
你就能和Sergei一起玩冰球了
you could be playing hockey with Sergei
而不是坐着这里
instead of learning the difference
研究勾手跳和后内跳的区别了
between a lutz and a salchow.
行了 你不用为我操心
All right, don't you worry about me.
你把自己装成一个顶尖的体育经纪人就成了
You just focus on becoming a top sports agent.
骗子还能拿到10%的回扣? 我肯定没问题
Con men taking 10%? I think I can handle it.
好吧 你的意思是
Okay, let me get this straight.
你要在一天之内成为一个花样滑的专家级教练?
You need to become an expert figure skating coach in a day?
错 我只需要看起来像就行了
No, I just need to look the part
然后在学一些必要技能
And learn enough to pass muster.
那么.... 你打算怎么帮我?
So... what can you tell me?
- 我?  - 对
- Me?  - Yeah.
你要让我在一天内把你训练成一个教练?
You want me to coach you to become a coach?
没错 亲爱的 你看了那么多花样游泳的比赛
Yeah. Honey, you have watched enough figure skating
都能担任下一任世界比赛的解说员了
to do color commentary on the next world championship.
是啊 我们通常称之为纸上谈兵
Yeah, that's what we call an armchair expert.
亲爱的 说跟做是不一样的
Honey, that is a world away from actually doing it.
你还记得吗... 我第一次滑冰
You remember... First time I was on the ice,
- 是我们第二次约会  - 记得
- it was our second date.  - Hmm.
我怎么能忘了呢?
How could I forget?
你本来该好好教我的
You were supposed to teach me.
呃 我怎么能做到?
Well, how could I?
你像小鹿斑比一样四仰八叉躺在冰上...
You were sprawled out on the ice like bambi...
看起来可爱极了
and looking just as adorable.
反应够快啊
Good save.
好吧 我们这样来
All right, this is what we're gonna do.
先从基本的开始
We're gonna start with the basics.
进度快的话 午夜能到
Then we're gonna move to Tonya Harding
Tonya Harding和Nancy Kerrigan(世界级花样滑选手)
and Nancy Kerrigan, hopefully by midnight.
好呀 以后有空
Uh-huh, and then one day,
我一定教你滑冰
I will finally teach you how to skate.
哦 不 这个案子一结
Oh, no, you're gonna teach me how to skate
你就得教我
as soon as this case is over.
我看起来怎么样?
How do I look?
像个联邦调查局的会计
Like an FBI accountant.
Gruetzner探员故意穿得很保守
Agent Gruetzner's conservative attire
以图掩饰他的破坏力
is just an attempt to disguise
和波西米亚人的身份
his subversive and Bohemian proclivities.
别夸大其辞了 Moz
Ah, don't overplay this, Moz.
又不是晚餐剧院
It is not dinner theatre.
不过就是回答几个问题罢了
You just need to answer a few simple questions.
我可是大师级的即兴表演家
I'm a master improviser.
我要出演一个完美且苛求的主管
I will be the perfect exigent supervisor.
你说了很多遍了
That sounds familiar.
当然 这可不是第一次
Yeah, it's not the first time
我穿上这身行头
the suit's gotten under my skin.
我刚刚从苛求的主管那得到消息
I just heard from the exigent supervisor.
好像Sergei想要改成明天在一个伏特加酒吧见面
Looks like Sergei wants to meet at a vodka bar tomorrow,
这下坏事了
And that's a problem.
我同一时间必须待在小奥德萨
I need to be in Little Odessa at the same time
还答应了陪Rebecca去见你
I promised Rebecca a meeting with you.
你错了 在我看来 这正是我们的机会
You say problem, I say opportunity.
你就不用被束缚了
You'll be off leash.
你可以偷偷溜走 猫咪探长却不知道
You can slip away, and big brother will be none the wiser.
确实 我们有办公室吗?
True. Do we have an office yet?
有 而且不远
Yeah, and it's not far.
Gravich医生 我的前任脊椎指压治疗师
Dr. Gravich, my former chiropractor
也是所有脊椎病患者的救星
and hero to ambulance chasers everywhere
每天下午一点到两点
takes his entire staff out to lunch
都会带上所有员工去吃午餐
from 1:00 until 2:00 every day.
一个脊椎指压治疗师的办公室?
A chiropractor's office?
再来些海报和各种人像
With some posters and sundry accoutrements,
也挺不错的
it'll look the part.
为了不让她问太多问题
And to keep her from asking too many questions,
我们可以给她看看法典
we can show her the codex.
她可是Mosconi专家啊
She is a mosconi expert.
所以在你害她丢了工作前
That's why she started working at the museum.
- 她在博物馆工作  - 也许如果让她
- until you got her fired.  - Maybe she'll forgive us
看上一眼我们的法典章节 就会原谅我们
if we give her a little peek at our chapter.
这样你就能弥补自己的过失
So you can reward her for your misdeed
而她也能提供我们想要的情报了
by having her reward us with her information.
- 嗨?  - 哦!
- Hello?  - Oh!
我们的演员来了
Here comes one of our accoutrements now.
快来跟我们艺术品犯罪小组的迷人接待员打个招呼
Say hello to the art crimes division's comely receptionist.
这里是联邦调查局 请问需要什么帮助?
FBI. May I help you?
好吧
All right.
好吧 Jones和特别行动小组
All right, Jones and the Tac team
在几个街区以外的一辆货车上
are in a van a few blocks away.
再近可能会威胁到我们的安全
Any closer and I think it'd be too risky.
没错 但你喝了半瓶伏特加之后更危险
Yeah, no riskier than you after half a bottle of vodka.
- 什么?  - 所以我才做了这个
- What?  - Which is why I made these.
不 听着... 不能耍花招
No, look... No tricks.
- 我自己能解决  - 怎么?
- I can handle myself.  - What?
- 真的?  - 真的
- Really?  - Yes.
你上次喝伏特加是什么时候?
When was the last time you did a shot?
我才没有... 是Hughes的退休派对
I don't... It was Hughes's retirement party.
- 我们喝了三杯  - 哦 三杯? 才三杯
- We did three of them.  - Ooh, three? Three.
- 是的  - 在俄罗斯的传统里
- Yes.  - Well, in Russia it's customary
喝酒就要喝光一整瓶
to drink until the bottle is empty.
好吧? 这辈子能让你保持清醒 不得罪Sergei
Okay? This will keep us sober without insulting Sergei.
Neal 我才不需要你的特技杯
Neal, I don't need your trick glasses.
没问题 但是 呃
No problem, but, uh,
我想也许我不应该戴着脚铐进去
I probably shouldn't walk in there with this.
谢谢
Thank you.
他不在这儿
He isn't here.
Neal Caffrey! 你个混蛋
Neal Caffrey! You bastard.
我和他妹妹好过 是个芭蕾舞演员
I dated his sister. The ballerina.
为啥你的恋爱史到头来总能影响到我?
Why does your love life always end up affecting me?
在他暴露咱俩身份之前把他弄走
Get him out of here before he blows our cover.
- 然后在外面等我  - 嘿!
- And wait for me right outside.  - Hey!
Dimitri! 见到你很高兴
Dimitri! So good to see you.
你再没给我妹妹打过电话
You never call my sister.
- 我应该宰了你  - 好了 好的
- I should kill you.  - All right, okay.
别紧张 好吧?
Take it easy now, all right?
我们都知道我只是大多数中的一员
You and I both know I was one of many.
你什么意思 "大多数中的一员"?
What do you mean, "one of many"?
我妹妹是圣徒
My sister is a saint.
- 我演得怎么样?  - 很好
- How was that?  - It was perfect.
- 好得不能再好了  - 口音是不是太重了?
- It could not have gone better.  - Was the accent too thick?
不 没有 很好了
No, it wasn't. It was great.
你肯定能通过"屋顶上的提琴手"试镜
You're gonna nail that Fiddler on the Roof audition.
- 谢谢  - 试镜加油 伙计
- Thanks.  - Break legs, kid.
嘿 我把脚铐和Peter都甩了
Hey, I ditched the anklet and Peter.
我这就过去
I'm on my way.
你那个花言巧语的朋友呢?
Where is your fast-talking friend?
哦 有急事呢
Oh, something urgent came up.
你知道经纪人... 总是到处灭火
You know agents... always putting out fires.
嗯 我们要鱼子酱 烤肉串
Uh, bring us the caviar, shashlik,
再来一碟腌蘑菇
and a plate of pickled mushrooms.
- 所以 你叫Peter Nevins  - 没错
- So, Peter Nevins  - Yeah?
是明星花样滑冰教练
Figure skating coach to the stars.
Nikolai 过来
Nikolai.
只有一点问题
There is just one little problem.
是什么?
What's that?
你似乎并不存在
You don't seem to exist.
如果都没有你这个人
Now, how can you be famous
你是怎么有名的呢?
if you don't exist?
这倒是真的
That's true.
Peter"Neevens"确实不存在
Peter"Neevens" doesn't exist.
但是... Peter Nevins...
But... Peter Nevins...
这么拼 N-e-v-i-n-s...
N-e-v-i-n-s...
存在
he does.
这是个可以理解的错误
It's an understandable mistake.
如果把让我用西里尔字母的键盘
If I were put in front of a cyrillic alphabet keyboard,
我... 嗯 我不能
I'd... well, I wouldn't...
我也拼不出"为了我们的健康"
I wouldn't be able to get past na zdorovie.
为了我们的健康
Na zdorovie.
你可能认为
You'd think art crimes
艺术品犯罪小组更需要舒适的办案环境
would call for a more aesthetically pleasing setup,
但我们选了华尔街附近的地方
but we take a backseat to Wall Street.
下午好 Caffrey探员
Good afternoon, Agent Caffrey.
这是June
And this is June.
我们部门没她就无法运行
Our office couldn't function without her.
- 他可没夸大其实  -  Lowe女士
- He's not exaggerating.  - Ms. Lowe.
Gruetzner特工 我们正恭候您的到来
Agent Gruetzner. We've been expecting you.
我和Gruetzner探员说过了
I filled Agent Gruetzner in on our talk.
我对我们局可能造成的麻烦表示抱歉
I'm sorry for any problems the bureau may have caused.
这里有你要的证明信
I have the letter you requested,
还有我的名片
along with my card,
以防任何潜在的雇主
in case any potential employers
需要电话查证
need to call to verify.
谢谢 呃...
Thank you. Uh...
但我还是希望能有个交代
but I'm still looking for closure.
我还有一些问题
I have some questions.
我们能单独谈谈吗?
Could we, um, speak privately?
事实上 我们有些事要跟你说
Actually, there's something we'd like to talk to you about.
你结婚了 是吗?
You're married, yes?
- 是的 非常幸福  - 那很好
- Yeah. Happily.  - That's good.
因为 Katya是很多
Because Katya is a woman
男人的梦中情人
many men desire.
她以前有个教练是单身
She once had a coach who was single.
他们整天练习
They would spend hours practicing,
经常练到深夜
often late into the night.
非常晚
Very late.
他现在滑得可不咋样了
He no longer skates so well.
嗯 那你应该看看如果我错过晚餐
Well, you should see what my wife does to me
我老婆会怎么教训我
when I miss dinner.
- 那很好  - 是的
- That's good.  - Yeah.
- 嗯 有时候  - 是的
- Well, sometimes.  - Yeah.
噢
Oh.
但是现在法典都不知道
But the codex has been hidden away
被藏到了哪里
its entire existence.
法典的主人严格禁止任何人打开它
The owner strictly forbade anyone from opening it.
你们... 是怎么弄到副本的?
How... how did you get a copy?
这是机密
That's classified.
恐怕你只能知道一些基本情况
I'm afraid you're on a need-to-know basis.
就是说 我们需要知道你所知道的
As in, we need to know what you know
而你却不能反过来
and not the other way around.
如果你愿意的话
If you're willing,
联邦调查局需要你的协助
the FBI would like your assistance
来破解它的含义
deciphering its meaning.
它可以帮助解决一个重大案件
It could help us solve a very serious case.
还有一件小事必须要跟你
There is one small matter that you need to be
说清楚
made aware of.
有一个非常危险的罪犯
There's a dangerous criminal
想要法典里的情报
who wants the information in the codex,
我们得弄清楚为什么
and we need to figure out why.
时间宝贵
And time is of the essence.
你知道吗? 你喝起酒来像俄国人
You know what? You drink like Russian.
- 谢谢  - 嗯 差不多
- Thank you.  - Well, almost.
你从明天开始工作
You start tomorrow.
明天很好
Tomorrow's good.
- 很好  - 很好
- Good.  - Good.
现在 我来给你点建议
Now, let me give you some advice.
只管滑冰 别管我的闲事
Stay on the ice and out of my business.
明白
Understood.
所以有个危险的罪犯
So a dangerous criminal is interested
对Mosconi法典感兴趣?
in the Mosconi Codex?
我们只是不想让你在毫不知情的状态下
We just wouldn't want to put you in harm's way
就以身犯险
unless you knew what you were getting into.
联邦调查局会保护你的
The FBI will protect you.
听着 我知道在你们看来
Look, I know I might just seem like
我可能只是个书呆子
another bookworm to you guys,
但我可以保护自己
but I can hold my own.
我只是需要时间考虑一下
I just need time to think about it.
你有我的名片 决定了就打电话给我
You have my card. Call with your decision.
但要快点
Just make it soon.
- 时间紧迫  - 我送你下去
- Every minute counts.  - I'll go down with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们还有两分钟!
We got two minutes!
恩 Neal?
Hmm. Neal?
人呢?
Neal?
嘿 顺利吗?
Hey. How'd it go?
我让你在门口等我的
I told you to wait right outside.
我知道 但我觉得你喝了那么多伏特加
Yeah, I figured you could use some coffee
喝杯咖啡比较好
after all that vodka.
我在街角找到个不错的咖啡馆
I found a great little place down the street.
那儿的图拉姜饼很好吃
Amazing Tula gingerbread.
- 你醉了吗?  - 不 我没醉
- Are you inebriated?  - No, I'm not inebriated.
拿着
Here.
你去把车开过来
Get the car. You're driving.
知道吗 酒精会放大
You know how alcohol tends to amplify
某些性格特点?
certain personality traits?
- 把车开过来 Neal  - 就去
- Get the car, Neal.  - I'm on it.
那个Peter Nevins的简历做得不错
Good work on that Peter Nevins bio.
幸好他们没提前五分钟搜索
It's a good thing they didn't check five minutes earlier.
那时候数据还在上传
We were still uploading.
Neal开小差了 对吧?
Neal took off, didn't he?
没错 我想跟着他的
Yeah, he sure did. I wanted to follow,
但又不放心留你一个人在里面和Sergei会面
but I didn't want to leave you in there with Sergei.
找出他去了哪儿
Find out where he went.
明白
Will do.
早上好
Morning.
- 有时间吃早饭吗?  - 我快迟到了
- Time for breakfast?  - Uh, I'm running late.
有一叠大小跟畸形婴儿一样的
I've got a stack of ASAC files
主管文件等着我去看呢
the size of an oddly shaped child.
要知道 我们当时说到这份工作的时候
You know, when we, um, we talked about this job,
我还以为是...
I was actually thinking, "wow...
"预先安排好的日程
predictable schedule.
合理的工作时间"
Reasonable hours."
结果又变成了从早到晚加班加点
And now it's back to late nights and early mornings
还得去喝伏特加
and vodka rooms.
更不用提那些穿着小短裙的花样滑冰选手
To say nothing about the figure skaters in short skirts.
噢 她们不合我胃口
Well, she's not my type.
我更喜欢小鹿斑比那样的
I'm more into the bambi kind of thing.
对啊 两手不协调 随便乱挥
Mm, the uncoordinated limbs sprawled.
正是如此
Exactly.
你没事吧?
You okay?
亲爱的...
Hon...
你每天出门工作...
every day you're in the field...
而我每天...
every day, I...
晚上没听到你回家
I can't exhale until I hear you
就没法松这口气
walk through that door at night.
我不喜欢这种感觉
And I don't like that feeling.
Siegel探员被谋杀只是随机的暴力事件
Agent Siegel's murder was a random act of violence.
可能发生在任何人身上
Could have happened to anybody.
没错
Mm-hmm.
但我不会出事的
But it's not gonna happen to me.
我保证
I promise.
没事了吧?
We good?
我迫不及待想听你给她些什么建议了
Can't wait to hear your notes on how to improve that.
我不会给训练建议
I don't have to give notes.
只是在假装罢了
I only have to pretend to give notes.
临时抱佛脚
Mm, kneeling at the anklet of the master
看来还是有用的
has taught you well.
所以大师在嚼口香糖?
The master is chewing gum?
我在进入角色
I'm getting into character.
- 这样  - 我是Neal Micali
- Oh.  - I'm Neal Micali.
他紧张的时候就会嚼口香糖
He chews gum when he's nervous.
我可不需要背景故事
I don't need a backstory.
我去找找看Sergel做假护照的工作室
I'm gonna go try to find Sergel's passport workshop.
嘿... 动作快点
Hey... make it quick.
Sergei不喜欢别人在这儿乱晃悠
Sergei doesn't like anyone nosing around.
你还是省省力气做教练吧
Save your coaching for the ice.
准备好了吗 教练?
You ready, coach?
好了
Yeah.
你可以相信我们
You can trust us.
但你得老实告诉我
But you have to tell me everything
Sergei在做什么生意
about Sergei's business.
我只知道他带了很多坏人
All I know is that he brings terrible people
来小奥德萨
to Little Odessa.
他想控制这块地方
He wants to control it.
所有人都害怕他
Everyone is scared of him.
那你为什么要和他在一起?
Then why are you with him?
起初他是个好人
In the beginning, he was a good man.
我从莫斯科搬过来和他住一起
I moved from Moscow to be with him.
现在他把我当成了所有物
Now he treats me like possession.
上星期 他觉得我在外面沾花惹草
Last week, he thought I cheated on him.
所以他... 打了我
So he... hit me.
接着第二天 他就跟什么都没发生过似的
And the next day, like nothing happened,
要我嫁给他
he asks me to marry him.
你怎么说的?
What did you say?
如果我答应了...
If I say yes...
这辈子就完了
I'll be miserable forever.
但如果我拒绝了...
And if I say no...
就死定了
I'm dead.
你是我的教练
You're my coach.
有什么建议?
You have advice?
嘿 Piotr!
Piotr!
嘿 Sergei
Sergei.
我以为你不会来得那么早呢
I didn't expect you here so early.
你觉得我会看都不看
You think I could just let you coach
就让你做我最爱女人的教练吗?
the love of my life without a little observation?
我很好奇你怎么看
I'm curious to know what you think.
Katya做后内跳的时候有些问题
So Katya's had trouble executing her salchow.
我觉得问题出在她用内刃落地时
In my opinion, the problem is her center of gravity
自己的重心
when she lands on the inside edge.
那可是大问题
Well, that would be a problem.
后内跳跳时一般都是用外刃着地的
The salchow always lands on the outside edge.
她只需要小小调整一下
All she needs is a slight adjustment.
三周跳时 她用于平衡的那只脚
The extension of her free foot on the three spin
伸得不够开
tends to be a bit shallow.
好了 看你的了
Okay. Work your magic.
听我说 落地时
Now, listen, make sure
把那条腿伸展开来
that you keep that extension long.
伸展开来
Think long.
试试看 相信自己 好吗?
Go skate. Trust yourself, all right?
别忘了盯紧这个家伙
Don't forget to keep an eye on this guy.
跳
And push.
不错 不错
Not bad. Not bad.
但也不完美
But not perfect either.
比赛时你必须做到完美
In competition, you gotta be flawless.
我们会接着练习的
We'll keep working on it.
对她严厉点 她需要学学什么叫纪律
Don't go easy on her. She needs to learn discipline.
呃 Sergei
Uh, Sergei.
我包里带了冰球鞋
I got my hockey skates in the bag.
Katya可以休息一下 我们俩赛一场
Katya can take a break while I give you a few pointers.
你们美国人就是这样失去优势的
That's why you Americans are losing your edge.
总是玩 不工作
All play and no work.
好吧 我明白了 明白了
Oh, okay. I get it, I get it.
你是不想让历史重演
You don't want a repeat of miracle on ice.
美国队重挫俄国队
The U.S. kicks Russia's ass again.
这可是俄国人心里永远的痛 Peter
That's an open wound for many of my countrymen, Peter.
把我的冰球鞋拿来 我们冰场上见
Get my skates. See you on the ice.
太好了
Excellent.
找到了
Bingo.
Jack 那是你97年在布鲁塞尔...
Jack, that is the same line that you sold Katarina...
- 嘿!  - 卖给Katarina的同一款式 对吧?
- Hey!  - In Brussels in '97, all right?
- 你在干嘛  - 嘿 我手机没电了
- Hey, you.  - Hey, my cell phone died.
明白吗? 能... 借下电话吗?
All right? Can... do you mind?
嘿 伙计 听着 我还在倒时差呢 懂吗?
Hey, pal, listen, I'm jetlagged, all right?
我们这就把事情解决
So let's close this out,
否则我就去找你的对手公司
or I'm gonna have to call your competition.
现在出去
Out. Now.
你知道这是什么吗?
Do you know what this is?
这是给Katya签约的条款记录
It's a deal memo for Katya.
一份不错的工资 奖金
A generous salary, bonuses and bumps,
旅行 美食 房子 衣服
travel, food, lodging, wardrobe.
你先别吵
Now, get lost.
否则你就去跟Sergei解释
Or you can explain to Sergei
Katya为什么要整晚哭泣了
why Katya will be crying into her sequins all night.
我听着呢 抱歉
Yeah, I'm back. Sorry.
没错
Mm-hmm.
稍等 Jack
Hold on, Jack.
给你两分钟 我再回来的时候 你最好已经走了
Two minutes. I come back, you be gone.
好的
All right.
对 对 我没挂
Yeah. Yeah, I'm still here.
只是稍微让我的耳朵清静清静
Just, uh, cleaning my ears out from all the manure
因为这十分钟你一直都在说废话
you've been shoveling into them for the last ten minutes.
能给你做示范可真是高兴
Oh, it's nice showing you how it's done.
五球四进 Peter
Four out of five, Peter.
祝你好运
I wish you good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
好好看着球
Keep your eye on the puck.
一球
That's one.
真不赖
Not too bad.
但我们是三局两胜
But we're playing best of three.
玩五局三胜好了
Oh, let's make it best of five.
嘿 Vanya
Vanya.
嘿 Seryozha
Seryozha.
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
那球射偏了
That one got away.
知道吗? 你真是个疯子
You know what? You're a crazy person.
但我喜欢
But I like that.
我们明天接着比
I'll finish with you tomorrow.
我现在有生意要做
I have business to take care of.
Ivan被保释了
Ivan made bail.
我怎么不知道?
Why wasn't I told about this?
法庭放弃了诉讼
The court dropped the ball.
显然有人没看到
Someone didn't get the memo
我们要对此展开调查的备忘提醒
that we've got an open investigation.
说到这个 冰球王
By the way, Gretzky,
你是故意让球击中围栏的
did you mean for the puck to hit the wall,
还是你想打Sergei却射偏了?
or were you trying to hit Sergei and missed?
你该来靶场看看
You should come to the firing range.
相信我 他从来不会射偏
Trust me. He never misses.
谢谢
Thank you.
Neal拿的复印件上的名字
The names on the printout Neal grabbed
和俄罗斯情报局的监视名单上的人吻合
match fugitives on the Russian intel watch list.
冰球场和莫斯科之间
Calls between the ice rink and Moscow
上周通过不少电话
shot up in the past week.
看来Sergei又要招新人了
Looks like Sergei's bringing in new recruits.
他们用新身份
They'll be untraceable
安全通过海关后 就没法再找到他们了
the minute they get through customs with new identities.
然后呢?
Yes?
如果我们不尽快捣毁Sergei的组织
So if we don't crack Sergei's network soon,
一大群俄罗斯罪犯
a bunch of hardened Russian criminals
就会涌进美国境内
will go into the wind on U.S. soil.
已经进来够多了
Seems like enough of them already have.
走吧
Come on.
纽约警局今天早上把Ivan的尸体从东河
Ivan was pulled out of the east river this morning
捞了起来
by NYPD.
他们果然是要杀人灭口
They didn't trust him not to talk.
俄罗斯情报局同意引渡
Russian intelligence agreed to extradite
所有已经在纽约的Sergei的手下
all of Sergei's men who were already in New York.
如果有新护照
With the clean passports,
根本不可能找到他们
they're gonna be almost impossible to find.
我们以前处理过洗钱案
We've dealt with money laundering before,
但Sergei在洗人
but Sergei's laundering people.
所以... 我们怎么逮捕一群散布城市四处
So... how do we round up a bunch of fearless Russians
还毫无畏惧的俄罗斯人?
who are scattered throughout the city?
还得在他们互相通风报信前
Before they tip each other off.
这得耗费很多人力
It's gonna take a lot of manpower
做足准备工作
and a lot of preparation,
而且咱们时间不够了
and we're running out of time.
何不让Sergei自己把他们交出来?
What if Sergei brings him to us?
洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
这么说吧 哪件事是这帮人最无法抗拒的?
Well, what's the one thing his guys can't resist?
找个由头搞派对
An excuse to party.
那咱们就帮他们找个理由让他们好好庆祝庆祝
So let's give them something to celebrate.
好的
Okay.
或许我们可以给Sergei
Maybe provide Sergei with the answer
- 他一直在等待的那个答复  - 是说Katya吗?
- he's been waiting for.  - Katya?
要是连这么大的喜事
What kind of fiance would he be
他都不开个派对庆祝一下
if he didn't throw a party to celebrate
- 还算得上什么好未婚夫?  - 好主意
- the happiest day of his life?  - Nice.
的确不算 太好了
He would not be a good one. That's excellent.
咱们把他们同时召集到一处
We put them all together in one place at the same time,
顺便可以帮小奥德萨摆脱Sergei的控制
and we put an end to Sergei's grip on Little Odessa.
我答应
I'll do it.
好的 Katya
All right, Katya,
我保证你不会有事的
I will make sure that nothing happens to you.
但我必须知道
But I need to know from you
你是否为此做好了准备
if you are really up for this.
还是个孩子的时候我每天早上5点就要爬起来
I woke up at 5:00 every morning as a child.
在雪中走上6英里才能到体育馆
Walked to the gym in the snow six miles away.
练习的时候 我的脚趾在溜冰鞋里流血
At practice, my toes bled in my skates.
但我依旧每天强颜欢笑
But I put on a smile every day.
这不算什么
This is nothing.
嘿 Sergei!
Sergei!
Peter帮助我认清了我之前是多么愚笨
Peter helped me see how stupid I have been.
我真不相信居然花了我这么久才决定
I can't believe it has taken me so long.
没错... 我愿意嫁给你!
Yes... I will marry you!
今晚咱们庆祝庆祝
Tonight, we celebrate.
- 他的朋友还真不少  - 嗯
- He has a lot of friends.  - Mm-hmm.
不可能全是罪犯吧
They can't all be criminals.
回了总部我们会甄别一番的
We'll do some weeding at headquarters.
Peter! 嘿 到这儿来
Peter! Hey. Come here.
你能赏脸过来真好
I'm so glad you could make it.
我还想见见您的爱人呢
I was hoping to meet your lovely wife.
我代她向您道歉 她得了流感 病得不轻
Ah, she sends her regrets. She came down with the flu.
太遗憾了 那只能婚礼上见了
Ah, too bad. Maybe at the wedding.
有可能吧
Maybe.
你表弟不留下来参加派对了吗?
Your cousin isn't sticking around for the celebration?
"无奔波 不生活"
"Life is a place of service."
你读托尔斯泰吗?
Do you read Tolstoy?
"战争与和平" 我的最爱之一
Ah, "War and Peace", one of my favorites.
别光顾着说呀
Ah, enough talk. Huh?
咱们开始庆祝吧
Let's celebrate.
Nikolal要走了 拖住他
Nikolal's leaving. Stall him.
我得抓住他 作为给她的订婚礼物
I want him to be here for her engagement present.
可那样我就听不到你的精彩演说了
But I'll miss your speech.
放心 有人会录下来的
I'll make sure somebody records it.
最好如此
You better.
呃 打扰一下
Uh, excuse me.
打扰一下 抱歉了 打扰一下
Excuse me. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
我叫Peter Nevins
I'm Peter Nevins.
你们都不认识我 我是Katya的教练
None of you know me, but I am Katya's coach.
我想在此祝福我的新朋友Sergei
And I just want to congratulate my new friend Sergei
和他动人可爱 天赋异禀的未婚妻Katya
and his lovely, talented fiance Katya.
喔 嚯!
Aww. Oh ho!
嘿 老兄!
Hey, buddy!
我是Neal Micali
It's Neal Micali.
别走啊 派对刚开始呢
Come on, the party's just getting started.
什么事这么急啊?
Where's the fire, my man?
嘿 我觉得咱们没好好认识认识
Hey, I feel like we got off to a bad start.
要不咱俩回去
How about you and me go back up there,
再喝个几杯... 如何?
have a shot or three... What do you say?
我想说的是
So what I'm really trying to say is,
能把大家的长相和名字对上号真好
it's good to put all these names to faces.
举杯
So raise a glass.
还有件事
Oh, one other thing.
你们都被捕了
You're all under arrest.
联邦调查局! 都不许动! 举起手来!
FBI! Nobody move! Hands in the air!
趴下! 哇 哇!
Get down! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
你根本不是什么运动员经理
You're no sport agent.
是啊 你也不是什么"Sammy Jordache"?
Yeah, and you're not "Sammy Jordache"?
- 这也想得出?  - 哇 嘿!
- Really?  - Whoa, hey!
呃! 想都别想
Uhh! Don't even think about it.
退后
Back away.
- 把刀放下  - 退后
- Just put it down right now.  - Back away.
立刻把刀放下!
Put that knife down right now!
她在我手上!
I'm taking her with me!
现在有五把枪指着你!
You got five guns on you right now!
- 把刀放下!  - 啊!
- Put it down!  - Aah!
你没事吧?
You okay?
你说得对
You were right.
Peter Nevins根本不存在
Peter Nevins doesn't exist.
看样子... 这些人同样如此
By the looks of it... neither do any of these people.
我认得你
Remember my face.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
看来...
So...
- 你要回因斯布鲁克了  - 嗯
- off to Innsbruck.  - Yes.
肯定会很有意思的吧?
That should be an adventure, huh?
- 希望如此  - 嗯
- Oh, I hope so.  - Hmm.
最后还有什么建议吗 教练?
Any last advice, coach?
前外三周跳时注意身体外侧
Watch your leading edge on the double axel
贝尔曼旋转时
and be sure to not lock your knees
注意不要锁死膝盖
on the biellmann spin.
你自己都不知道自己在说什么吧?
Oh, you have no idea what any of that means, do you?
是不知道 在我拿来学习的解说DVD里有这句
No. A commentator once said it on my research DVDs.
说起来挺顺溜的
It sounded good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没事
Sure.
哦
Oh.
好运
Good luck.
- 我带你出去  - 谢谢
- I'll walk you out.  - Thank you.
拜
Bye.
发现什么了吗?
What'd you find?
离那个伏特加酒吧一个街区的监控像头
Surveillance cameras a block from the vodka room
拍到了一个的哥
led us to a cabbie.
是他把他们接到这来的
He picked them up and brought them in.
这地方有什么特别之处吗?
Anything special about the place?
没 只是普通的办公楼
Nah, it's just your average office building.
会计 治疗师 没什么反常的
Accountants, therapists. Nothing out of the ordinary.
会有什么吸引他过来的原因吗?
Is there any reason he'd slip away to come here?
Neal来一定是有原因的
Neal always has a reason.
- 哦 嘿  - 嘿
- Oh, hey.  - Hey.
你可以拉开你的降落伞了
You can pull the ripcord on your safety chute.
Rebecca刚才用临时手机打来电话了
Rebecca just called on the burner phone.
真的? 她说什么了?
Really? What did she say?
你声音里是藏着一丝欢脱吗?
Do I detect a lilt in your voice?
Gruetzner探员都看出来了 你喜欢她
Agent Gruetzner sees all. You like her.
别胡闹了 你还是六年级小孩吗?
What is this, sixth grade?
私以为 她没啥吸引人的
Personally, I don't see the attraction.
她不想抢劫你也不想逮捕你
She doesn't want to rob you or arrest you
也不想为保险欺诈起诉你
or charge you with insurance fraud.
你就跟我说她都说了什么吧
Just tell me what she said.
她想在藏书室跟你见面
She wants to meet at the rare book room.
要知道 没有什么比一位风姿绰约的女子
You know, there's nothing more enchanting
用纤纤玉手捧着一本古色古香的名作
than a beautiful woman cradling a classic opus
更让人欲罢不能的了
in her soft, gentle hands.
要不这次你来?
Would you like to take the lead on this one?
别 你才是主唱
No, you're the front man.
我只是个小小的吉他手
I'm merely rhythm guitar.
是啊 约翰·列侬也是
Yeah, well, so was John Lennon.
多谢夸奖
Thank you for that.
嘿
Hey.
别让心动坏了正事
Leave your heart off your sleeve.
- 有什么能帮你的吗?  - 嗯
- Can I help you?  - Yeah.
只是惯例检查
Uh, just a routine call.
这附近所有办公室我们都查了一遍
We're checking all the offices in the area.
最近几天这有发生什么怪事吗?
Anything unusual occur here in the last couple days?
如果椎间盘突出不算怪事的话 那就没有了
Not unless you consider a room full of herniated discs unusual.
嗯 我走走看看不要紧吧?
Hmm. Mind if I poke around?
亲爱的 随便走走看看吧
Honey, you go ahead and poke.
您好 Gravich医生的办公室 有什么能帮您的吗?
Hello, Dr. Gravich's office. How can I help you?
是哪里不舒服?
Well, what seems to be the problem?
呃... 星期四如何?
Um... how's Thursday?
从上午10点到下午5点他一直在
He's here from 10:00 a.m. till 5:00.
好的
Okay.
嗯
Hmm.
介意我越过肩膀和你一起看吗?
You mind if I read over your shoulder?
呃... 其实不是什么简单的阅读
Uh... it's not exactly light reading.
- 原来是Mosconi  - 没错
- Oh, Mosconi.  - Yeah.
我觉得咱们可以开始研究了
I figured we could, um, start our research.
也就意味着你做好决定了?
Does that mean you've come to a decision?
没错
Yes, it does.
我会帮助你们理解法典
I will help you with the Codex.
呃... 但是...
Um... but...
我得先跟你坦白
I should tell you something first,
- 免得你蒙在鼓里  - 说吧
- just so you know.  - Tell me.
我 呃...
I, um...
我服过刑
I did time.
真的?
Really?
- 哇  - 我那时才19岁
- Wow.  - I was 19.
那学期是在马拉喀什
It was a semester in Marrakesh.
我在Menara花园
So I'm in the Menara Gardens,
那有些非常漂亮的绿瓦
and there was this beautiful green tile.
什么 在Saadian亭吗?
What, in the Saadian Pavilion?
没错
Yes.
它从屋顶落下
So it had fallen off the roof,
我装口袋里带走了
and I pocketed it.
我一直想送回去的
And I always meant to take it back,
结果回去的时候...
and then when I tried...
你被抓了
You got pinched.
那是我一生中最吓人的一夜
It was the scariest night of my life.
呃 什么 才一夜?
Um, I'm sorry, "night"?
单数?
Singular?
- 没开玩笑...  - 在监狱过上一夜?
- Believe me...  - One night in jail?
在摩洛哥的监狱待上一夜够受的了
One night in a Moroccan prison is enough.
好吧
All right.
听着... 我和获释犯共事过
Look... we've worked with ex-cons before.
跟你一样久经沙场的
Even seasoned, hardened criminals,
惯犯
like yourself.
没遇到监狱里的饥渴变态吧?
Did you have a prison bitch?
嘘
Shh.
抱歉
Sorry.
为了完全揭秘
And, in the interest of full disclosure,
我... 觉得法典的副本是不完整的
I... look our copy of the codex is incomplete.
哦
Oh.
你手头有多少?
How much do you have?
只有一个章节 第13章
A single chapter. It's chapter 13.
有什么特别的想法吗?
Does that mean anything to you?
- 你知道吗?  - 什么?
- You know what?  - What?
我受够了
I'm done with games.
受够了? 你说什么呢?
Games? What are you talking about?
我... 我有说... 我有说什么吗?
I... did I say... what did I say?
来啊 打开看看 第13章
Go ahead. Open it. Chapter 13.
找不到? 试试这本
No luck? Try this one.
Mosconi极度迷信
Mosconi was incredibly superstitious.
他所写的所有书中
In all the books he ever produced,
从没出现过第13章
he never wrote a chapter 13.
就是这样
That's it.
你的水性回来了
You're getting your sea legs back.
早就不灵了
Frozen sea legs.
咱们这样真的不要紧吧?
Is it really okay that we're doing this?
理论上讲 这是犯罪现场
Well, technically, it's a crime scene,
所以不要乱碰东西
so don't touch anything.
好吧 再教我一遍怎么转身
Okay. All right, tell me how to turn again.
好 只需在外侧冰刀上加些力道
All right, just put pressure on the outside blade.
很好 然后倾斜身体
Yes. And lean.
哦! 就像这样!
Oh! Oh, like that!
就是这样 没错!
There you go. Yeah!
很好 哇 等等... 哇!
Good. Whoa. Wait, wait... whoa!
我抓住你了 抓住你了
I got you. I got you.
哇
Whoa.
没事 我抓住你了
Okay. I got you.
是啊 你一直抓得住我的
Yeah. You always do.
好吧
Okay.
--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
时间轴: pisces夜
翻译: 花孔雀 初见 落寞卷菜 猫鼠小贝 爱鼠影 捞小盐
校对: 爱鼠影
这下有点像咱们第二次约会了
Kind of like our second date.
还再美妙点呢
Little better.